Finding Aid for the Ernst Toch Papers PASC-M.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ernst Toch papers
circa 1835-1988
UCLA Library Special Collections
Toch, Ernst 1887-1964
PASC-M.0001
44 linear feet (88 boxes)
The Collection consists of materials relating to the Austrian-American composer, Ernst Toch. Included are music manuscripts and scores, books of his personal library, manuscripts, biographical material, correspondence, articles, essays, speeches, lectures, programs, clippings, photographs, sound recordings, financial records, and memorabilia. Also included are manuscripts and published works of other composers, as well as Lilly Toch's letters and lectures.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Lilly Toch; gift; 1966-1970.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942338723606533
Biographical Note
Ernst Toch was born on Dec. 7, 1887 in Vienna; taught himself piano in his grandmother's pawnshop; learned musical notation from a local violinist, and copied Mozart's string quartets for practice; began to compose chamber music, and at age 17 had a quartet performed; in 1909 he won the prestigious Mozart Prize and a scholarship to study at the Frankfurt Conservatory, where he studied piano with Willy Rehberg and composition with Iwan Knorr; won the Mendelssohn Prize in 1910 and the Austrian State Prize four times in succession; in 1913 he was appointed teacher of composition at the Mannheim Musikhochschule; married Lilly Zwack in 1916; earned Dr. phil. degree in 1921; taught piano and composition in Berlin from 1929-33, leaving at the onset of the Nazi regime for Paris, London, and finally the US, where he taught at the New School for Social Research in New York (1934-36); taught at the Univ. of Southern CA (1937-48), afterward giving private instruction; lived in Vienna and Switzerland from 1950-58, then spent the remainder of his life in LA; won the Pulitzer and Huntington-Hartford Prizes for his Third Symphony (1956), was elected to the American National Institute of Arts and Letters (1956), received honorary citations from the German and Austrian governments, and won a Grammy Award (1960); publications include Melodielehre (1923) and The shaping forces in music (1948); his compositions encompass all genres and include Fuge aus der Geographie (1930), Seven symphonies, 13 string quartets, several chamber operas, and music for films; he died on Oct. 1, 1964 in LA.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Photographic Material. 5 boxes
Series 2. Sound Recordings
Series 3. Correspondence
Series 4. Clippings and Programs
Series 5. Miscellaneous Printed Material
Series 6. Articles, Essays, Speeches, Lectures
Series 7. Music Manuscripts
Series 8. Toch Published Works
Series 9. Toch's Library: Books and Journals
Series 10. Toch's Library: Scores
Series 11. Interviews
Series 12. Realia and Miscellanous
Series 13. Lawrence Weschler Collection
Series 14. Toni Weschler Collection
Series 15. Recent Acquisitions
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials relating to the Austrian-American composer, Ernst Toch. Includes music manuscripts and scores, books of his personal library, manuscripts, biographical material, correspondence, articles, essays, speeches, lectures, programs, clippings, photographs, sound records, financial records, and memorabilia. Also included are manuscripts and published works of other composers, and Lilly Toch's letters and lectures.
Online Related Digital Materials
Ernst Toch, 1964. part of the James Arkatov photographs
Ernst Toch, 1964. part of the James Arkatov photographs
Ernst Toch reading a book, 1964. part of the James Arkatov photographs
Music -- Manuscripts.; Music -- Scores.; Sound recordings.; Composers -- Archives.; Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964--Archives.; Toch, Lilly, 1892-1972.
- Photographic Material, Series 1.; 5 boxes
  - Toch - Graf family photos, Subseries 1.; 1 boxes
    - Siegfried Toch (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Johann Toch (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Grossmutter Rosalia Toch (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Grossvater Elkan Toch (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - unidentified (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Grossmama Johanna Graf (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Grosspapa Gerson Lueb Graf (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mama, 19 years old (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - none (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Papa (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Grossmama, 14 years old (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Gisela, 7 years old (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - group photo: 1 - Tante Hinterstein, 2 - Mama, 3 - Ernst, 4 - me, 5 - Eugene, 6 - Erna, 7 - Edith (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Grossmama Graf (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Grosspapa Graf (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - meine Eltern, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - enlarged group photo (duplicate of 13) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tuni, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ernst Toch youth, 1887-1910; Subseries 2.
    - School photo (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents note
      Toch is center, 2nd row from top.
    - Toch playing piano, 10" x 12" (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Enlarged copy of Box 4, Item 24. Matted
    - Family portrait (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Ernst Toch (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Ernst with mother and sister, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      3 photos and duplicate
    - Toch at piano (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Photo and duplicate
    - Toch at the keys (Box 4, Folder 23)
      photo and duplicate
    - Toch playing piano (Box 4, Folder 24)
      photo and duplicate. Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 8.
    - After graduation from High School, after Mozart prize (Box 4, Folder 25)
      group photo
    - Ernst, age 21 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Ernst and Elsa, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Musical Patrons, 1910-1920; Subseries 3.
    The Amlingers
    - Bodausky, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Willy Rekberg, Toch's piano teacher in Frankfurt (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Henri Petri of Dresden, leader of the Petri-Quartett (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Amlinger (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Paul Amlinger (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Mr. Amlinger (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Mr. Amlinger (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - The Amlingers, Ferdinand and Paul (sons), Mr. and Mrs. Amlinger (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Lilly Zwack, 1912-1920; Subseries 4.
    Mrs. Toch. The series includes early photographs.
    - Toch and Lilly, 1916; 10" x 12" (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Toch with his fiancee, Lilly, around the time of their wedding July 23, 1916 (?). Picture of Mozart on table he carried with him everywhere, even to the trenches. Enlarged duplicate of Box 4, Item 47. Matted.
    - Austrian lake resort (Altersee): Lilly Toch with her sister Marianne and a friend., 1916 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Lilly 5 years old, Marianne 3 years old, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - house in Galicea, requisitioned by Army during truce with Russia, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - World War I picture (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lilly as nurse in World War I. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lilly Toch and sister Marianne on mountain excursion with guides before 1914 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Lilly as nurse in World War I. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Ernst and Lilly (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Ernst and Lilly with Ernst's mother and uncle in courtyard of Heidelberg Castle, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Ernst and Lilly posing in a tree with friend (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Ernst and Lilly (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Ernst and Lilly, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Toch with his fiancee, Lilly, around the time of their wedding July 23, 1916 (?). Picture of Mozart on table he carried with him everywhere, even to the trenches. 2 copies. Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 7.
    - Lilly and her sister Marianne, 4 and 7 years old (Box 4, Folder 48)
      3 copies.
    - Elsa Zwack, Lilly's mother (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Military, 1912-1918; Subseries 5.
    - Ernst in uniform (Box 4, Folder 50)
      3 copies
    - small portrait 1916 or 1917 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      2 copies
    - group photo in a pig yard (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - standing at attention (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - relaxing on a hill, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - portrait with a fellow officer (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - relaxing behind a desk (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - group photo, postcard sent to Gisela Toch (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - group photo, Toch is center first seated row (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - smoking cigarettes, picture of Mozart on desk (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Ernst at war (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - group photo (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - at a train stop (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - in the dining room (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Military portrait (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Military portrait (Box 4, Folder 64a)
    - young portrait (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - young portrait, profile (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Group photo (Box 4, Folder 66a)
      Toch holding dog. 2 copies.
    - in the dining room, Toch 2nd from rt (Box 4, Folder 66b)
  - Civilian, 1910-1920; Subseries 6.
    - German vacation pictures, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      set of 15 photos
    - portrait (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - portrait, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - working in his Berlin studio, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      3 photos
    - Toch on steps (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Toch arriving in New York on the Queen Mary for Pro Musica concert tour; with puppy, March 1932 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      2 photos
    - photo of Toch (Box 4, Folder 73)
      4 copies
    - Toch working, 1929? (Box 4, Folder 74)
      In his Berlin studio?
    - Toch (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Toch with family and friends, 1920-1930; Subseries 7.
    - Toch and his mother in Venice (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Toch and friend walking (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Photo backing, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      Fritz 24 years, Lilly 20 years, Franzi 4 years, Grossmama 70 years. (this is backing of Item 79)
    - Fritz, Grossmama, Lilly, Franzi, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Ernst Toch, Mannheim with Peter I. (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Lilly Toch (Box 4, Folder 81)
      photo and duplicate.
    - Photos, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      4 pictures of Franzi from letter to John Bass, 20 June 1930
    - Ernst and his sister, Elsa, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Ernst, Franzi and kitten, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 84)
      JPEG available: Box 5, Item 1.
    - Max, Hausi Stolper, Franzi Toch, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      Ventnor, August 1933.
    - Franzi at 2 years old, Ernst and Lilly, Grossmama (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Ernst and Lilly with dog (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Ernst Toch, Gustav and Toni Stolper, 5 February 1936 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Ernst and Franzi (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Ernst and Franzi (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - vacation photo album (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Publicity photos/portraits, Subseries 8.
    - Portrait, 1914; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Portrait, side angle, five 8" x 10", two 5"x7", photocopy (Box 1, Folder 2)
      7 copies and photocopy.
    - Reading book near piano, 1932; 3 1/2" x 5", 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Photo, negative and copy.
    - Portrait, 1952; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2" (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Side profile, reading book, 1956; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2" (Box 1, Folder 5)
      4 copies (2 per envelope)
    - Toch composing, 1958; 8"x10" (Box 1, Folder 6)
      3 copies. Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 9.
    - Side angle, wearing jacket, three 8"x10", one 3" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Toch with a letter and a book, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - With elbow propped on piano, 8"x10" (Box 1, Folder 9)
      3 copies and photocopy
    - Close-up, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Side profile, 3 1/4" x 5 1/4" (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Portrait, 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Portrait, 5" x 6" (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Portrait, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - With Daschund, 7" x 9" (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - With arms crossed, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Toch seated, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Portrait, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Seated with book, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Seated, reading book (Box 1, Folder 20)
      2 copies.
    - Portrait, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Portrait, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Portrait, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Smoking cigarette, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - In Mannheim studio, 1928; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 6.
    - At piano, c. 1930; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Berlin, 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Gazing out window, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 28)
      2 copies. Enlarged duplicate: Box 2, Item 10.
    - At his desk, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - holding his dog (Box 1, Folder 29a)
      JPEG available: Box 5, Item 2.
    - In Mannheim Studio, 1928; 11 1/2" x 15" (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Duplicate of Box 1, Item 25.
    - Toch composing, 1958; 14" x 11" (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Enlarged duplicate of Box 1, Item 6.
    - Gazing out window, 17" x 14" (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Enlarged duplicate of Box 1, Item 28. Matted.
  - Toch and others, 1930-1964; Subseries 9.
    - Seven photos, 1930; 2 1/2" x 3 1/2" (Box 1, Folder 30)
      from letter to John Bass, 20 June 1930. Toch with Regisseur and Spieler der Hauptrolle of opera "Der Faecher" presented in Koenigsberg. (Three photos)
    - Charles Wakefield Cadman, Mario Castelnuova-Tedesco, Henri Temianka, Toch, Miklos Rosa., 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Negative of Item 31. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Henri Temianka, Mario Castelnuova-Tedesco, Toch, Charles Wakefield Cadman., 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Negative of Item 33. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - In the Santa Monica Mountains: Otto Klemperer, Prinz Hubertus von Loewenstein, Arnold Schoenberg, Toch, 1937; two 3 3/4" x 5 1/2", two 8" x 10" and photocopy (Box 1, Folder 35)
      4 copies and photocopy
    - Negative of Item 35. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Toch, Arnold Schoenberg, Otto Klemperer, Prinz Hubertus von Loewenstein, 3 3/4" x 5 1/2" and negative (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Photo and negative
    - Toch, Arnold Schoenberg, Otto Klemperer, Prinz Hubertus von Loewenstein, one 3 3/4" x 5 1/2" one 8" x 10" and negative (Box 1, Folder 38)
      2 copies and negative
    - Franklin Street: Herbert Zipper, Ernst Toch, c. 1960; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Toch with Kurt Weill, 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 40)
      from Frankfurter Zeitung
    - Lotte Lenya and Toch, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - New York: Toch's 70th birthday celebration, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Friedrich (Carl?) Ebert (Glyndebourne), Lotte Lenya, Raymond Kendall, Ernst Toch, Feist(AMD), Huntington Hartford(?). 1 copy and photocopy.
    - Lotte Lenya and lady, 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 43)
      "Lotte Lenya, right, widow of Kurt Weill, and favoured star of his Three-Penny-Opera, at the 75th Birthday Musicale held in New York's new Austrian Institute on Dec. 18, honoring the great Vienna-born composer Ernst Toch who now lives in California"
    - George Gershwin, publicity photo (Box 1, Folder 43a)
    - Mrs. MacDowell, 2 1/2" x 3 1/4" (Box 1, Folder 43a)
      press clipping
    - Schoenberg close-up, 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 43b)
    - Eric Zeisl, 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 43c)
    - George Gershwin, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Inscribed to Toch by Gershwin.
    - Toch and Lilly with Holmboes during visit to Denmark, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 43e-h)
    - Alice Coleman Batchelder (Box 1, Folder 43i)
      Founder Coleman Chamber Concerts
    - Lilly at the Acropolis, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 43j)
    - Toch with friends at party (Box 1, Folder 43k)
    - Toch with Lilly, Marta Feutwaengler and others at party (Box 1, Folder 43l)
    - Ernst and Lilly with unknown friends, late 1940s (Box 1, Folder 43m)
    - Toch with group of composers (Box 1, Folder 43n)
    - Toch cutting cake at 75th birthday celebration, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 43o)
    - Toch with two others at 75th birthday celebration, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 43p)
    - Toch with Huntington Hartford, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 43q)
    - Toch at Hebrew Union College graduation exercises (Box 1, Folder 43r)
    - Toch recieving the National Institute of Arts and Letters Medal at USC, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 43s-u)
  - Sculpture and paintings, Subseries 10.
    - Lawrence Weschler next to a bust of his grandfather by Anna Mahler., 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Toch bust by Erich Kuhn., 4" x 6" (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Profile of Toch bust by Erich Kuhn., 1926; 4" x 6" (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Photo of sculpture of Toch by Anna Mahler. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Photo of sculpture of Toch by Anna Mahler, side angle. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Photo of Toch's portrait by Max Band, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Photo of Toch's portrait (in frame) by Max Band, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Toch bust by Erich Kuhn (Box 1, Folder 50b)
    - Photograph of A. Kaufmann painting of George Gershwin (Box 1, Folder 50c)
    - Toch bust by Erich Kuhn - side profile, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      duplicate of Box 1, Item 46. Matted.
    - Toch bust by Erich Kuhn., 1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Duplicate of Box 1, Item 45. Matted.
  - Rehearsal/ performance photographs, Subseries 11.
    - Toch with William Steinberg, Third Symphony rehearsal, 1955; one 3 1/2" x 5", two 8" x 10", negative (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Original photo, 2 copies and negative.
    - Close-up of Toch, 1955; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 52)
      from Item 51
    - Toch with Steinberg, 1955; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 53)
      2 photos.
    - Toch with Steinberg, 1955; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Toch at the 3rd Symphony rehearsal., 1955; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Toch with Steinberg (Box 1, Folder 55a)
    - Performance of Third Symphony (Box 1, Folder 55b)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", ca. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 56)
      (1 photo, 11 photos total.)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", ca. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 57)
      (2 photos, 11 photos total.)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", c. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", c. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", c. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Leipzig Staadtoper production of "The Princess and the Pea.", c. 1950; 5" x 7" (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Herbert Zipper's performance of "The Princess and the Pea," Chicago., c. 1950; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 62)
      (2 photos, 10 photos total)
    - Herbert Zipper's performance of "The Princess and the Pea," Chicago., c. 1950; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Herbert Zipper's performance of "The Princess and the Pea," Chicago., c. 1950; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Herbert Zipper's performance of "The Princess and the Pea," Chicago., c. 1950; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Herbert Zipper's performance of "The Princess and the Pea," Chicago., c. 1950; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Gateway Opera's production of "The Princess and the Pea.", 1970s (Box 1, Folder 66a-d)
      5 color photos and drawings of costumes.
    - Open-air concert of the Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 66e)
    - Performance of Cantata of the Bitter Herbs by LA City College (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Toch alone, 1950-1964; Subseries 12.
    - "In back of my "Sprague Smith" studio." and photo of building., 1953; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 67)
      2 photos. Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 1.
    - proofs, 2 1/4" x 2 1/4" (Box 1, Folder 68)
      5 casual poses of Toch (photo proofs).
    - Toch working on a manuscript., 4" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Close up of Toch., 1958; 4" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Toch, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 71)
      2 photos of Toch.
    - At home, seated near piano., 1958; 4" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - 2 photos of Toch., 4" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - photo of Toch., 1962; 7 1/2" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 74)
      Enlarged copy: Box 2, Item 2.
    - outside, looking at score., 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Seated, at home., 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Outside, holding dog, 1962; color 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 76a)
    - Seated; With dog (Box 1, Folder 76b)
    - "In back of my "Sprague Smith" studio, taken July 3, 1953.", 9" x 13 1/2" (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Enlargement of Box 1, Item 67.
    - photo of Toch (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Enlargement of Box 1, Item 74
  - Family pictures, c. 1950-1964; Subseries 13.
    Franzi and family; Lilly and Ren.
    - Toch playing chess with Iru Weschler., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Toch with grandchildren. (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Toch's grandchildren; Franzi with baby., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 79)
      (2 photos.)
    - Franzi's wedding. (Box 1, Folder 80)
      (4 photos.)
    - Franzi and Ernst with Lawrence., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 81)
      (4 photos)
    - 4 photos of Europe trip from a letter to John Bass., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Toch and Franzi. (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Two photo books from Franzi Weschler's funeral., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 84)
      Item moved to Miscellaneous Printed Materials: Obituaries.
    - Toch and Lilly with Franzi and grandchildren, 15 photos (Box 1, Folder 84a-c)
    - Lilly Toch., 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Lilly and Ren., 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Proofs of Lilly and Ren interview. (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Negatives of Lilly and Ren interview. (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Negatives of Lilly and Ren interview. (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Negatives of Lilly and Ren interview. (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Memorial booklet from Lilly Toch's funeral. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Residential photographs, Subseries 14.
    Santa Monica home and Zurhaus (Zurich).
    - hallway to living room, 1972; 3" x 4" (Box 1, Folder 92)
      Photos by Norm Schindler after Mrs. Toch died to show original arrangement.
    - Toch's desk, 1972; 4" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Entranceway, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 94)
      2 copies. Photos by Norm Schindler after Mrs. Toch died to show original arrangement.
    - Toch's desk and piano, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Toch's desk, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Living Room, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Piano and living room, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Toch's Library, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - hallway, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Dining Room, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Hallway into living room, 1972; 8" x 10" (Box 1, Folder 102)
      3 copies. Photos by Norm Schindler after Mrs. Toch died to show original arrangement.
    - Zurich: Zurhaus, 1997; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 103)
      Three colored pictures of the Zurhaus in Zurich where the Tochs often stayed in the 50s and 60s. Taken by Constanze Stratz.
    - Zurich: Zurhaus, 1997; 3 1/2" x 5" (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Toch's home in Mannheim, photocopy (Box 1, Folder 105)
      Toch's home is front/right. Gift of Heiko Schneider.
    - Santa Monica home from outside (Box 1, Folder 105a)
    - Photos of Berlin home (Box 1, Folder 105b)
    - Photos of Berlin home (Box 1, Folder 105c)
    - Close-ups of Toch's desk in Santa Monica home (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Close-ups of Toch's desk in Santa Monica home (Box 1, Folder 105e)
  - Photos in the press, Subseries 15.
    - "Some Composers Who Have Gone Hollywood" from Musical America, February 10, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)